<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>datavis on Calum Webb</title>
    <link>/tags/datavis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in datavis on Calum Webb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Calum Webb 2019 - 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/datavis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster: Visualising the Villagers, datavis meets Animal Crossing</title>
      <link>/posts/visualising-the-villagers-datavis-meets-animal-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/visualising-the-villagers-datavis-meets-animal-crossing/</guid>
      <description>As many have pointed out, the release of the anticipated Animal Crossing: New Horizons coincided with with the COVID-19 pandemic. Like many others I’ve been enjoying the experience of building an island paradise for my animal villagers, but I had to find something to do while waiting for my money rock to respawn, my fruits to regrow, and my bridges to be built.
Over the last week I’ve been scraping data from various Wikis and fan sources to put together a set of visualisations about the animals that inhabit the many digital islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday 21/01/2020: Spotifyr. Hierarchical clusters of popular songs by audio features</title>
      <link>/posts/spotifyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/spotifyr/</guid>
      <description>Playlist: https://open.spotify.com/playlist/3kPYr4522CKURLg4ePkuz1?si=3Yx-APApQL2s4KsvFFskAQ
Playlist: https://open.spotify.com/playlist/18qGN481uKhPCbBy0UHz1i?si=l5jqQlb0R5WD8HYv9UVIlA
Playlist: https://open.spotify.com/playlist/4ChD4YncnVzSK7E8Z8wn3W?si=JCJUSe55TNGREQ1q0QF9CQ
Playlist: https://open.spotify.com/playlist/2kdfe1C6wSRkNxhrEyIVOP?si=QRJbJofnRUyvib-_U4GSvA
Playlist: https://open.spotify.com/playlist/3FnznOoaA2lnDr7wIT0j5Q?si=lgcYDNeDSau2nnP0_ID92w
Playlist: https://open.spotify.com/playlist/7nwVFzZ67qgu1VddrbpQ5K?si=cWn4yU4pRj-k8H37icWRog
Playlists created using spotipy.
This was my attempt at creating an appealing (although maybe not super informative) visualisation of popular songs from the Spotify data in this week’s Tidy Tuesday.
If I was using my statistical routes, I would just describe this as a dendrogram with polar coordinates showing the results from a hierarchical cluster analysis based on several audio features: danceability, energy, loudness, speechiness, acousticness, instrumentalness, liveness, valence, and tempo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>